<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Mr. Kurzius</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Mr. Kurzius</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 10:20:37 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Menu</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 10:20:37 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/menu/</guid>
      <description> Home Classes&#xA;Algebra I AP Computer Science A Honors Calculus Intro to Programming Math Strategies Clubs&#xA;Esports </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Algebra I</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/classes/algebra-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/classes/algebra-1/</guid>
      <description>Algebra I&#xD;#&#xD;2023–2024&#xA;Course Description&#xD;#&#xD;This course focuses on deepening understanding of linear and exponential relationships by contrasting them with each other. Students will apply linear models to data that exhibit a linear trend, and also engage in methods for analyzing, solving, and using quadratic functions.&#xA;Units of Study&#xD;#&#xD;1 Limits and Continuity Explore how limits allow solving problems involving change and to better understand mathematical reasoning about functions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AP Computer Science A</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/classes/ap-csa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/classes/ap-csa/</guid>
      <description>AP Computer Science A&#xD;#&#xD;2023–2024&#xA;Course Description&#xD;#&#xD;AP Computer Science A introduces students to computer science through programming. Fundamental topics in this course include the design of solutions to problems, the use of data structures to organize large sets of data, the development and implementation of algorithms to process data and discover new information, the analysis of potential solutions, and the ethical and social implications of computing systems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bell Schedules</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bell-schedules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bell-schedules/</guid>
      <description>Bell Schedules 2023–2024&#xD;#&#xD;P Startn Endn Starte Ende Startd Endd 1 08:00 08:48 08:00 08:31 10:00 10:34 2 08:51 09:35 08:34 09:04 10:36 11:06 3 09:38 10:22 09:07 09:37 11:08 11:38 4 10:25 11:09 09:40 10:10 11:40 12:10 5 11:12 11:56 10:13 10:43 12:12 12:42 6 11:59 12:43 10:46 11:16 12:44 13:14 7B 12:46 13:30 11:19 11:49 13:16 13:46 8L 13:33 14:03 11:52 12:22 13:48 14:18 9 14:06 14:50 12:25 12:55 14:20 14:50 \(f(x) = x^2\)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Honors Calculus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/classes/calculus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/classes/calculus/</guid>
      <description>Honors Calculus&#xD;#&#xD;2023–2024&#xA;Course Description&#xD;#&#xD;Explore the concepts, methods, and applications of differential and integral calculus. You’ll work to understand the theoretical basis and solve problems by applying your knowledge and skills. You&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to determine expressions and values using mathematical procedures and rules; connect representations; justify reasoning and solutions; and use correct notation, language, and mathematical conventions to communicate results or solutions.&#xA;Units of Study&#xD;#&#xD;1 Limits and Continuity Explore how limits allow solving problems involving change and to better understand mathematical reasoning about functions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Programming</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/classes/intro-to-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/classes/intro-to-programming/</guid>
      <description>Intro to Programming&#xD;#&#xD;2023–2024&#xA;Course Description&#xD;#&#xD;A computer is basically lightning trapped inside a rock and programming is telling the lighting what it should do. This one-semester course is for those with an interest in computer programming, whether it’s a career goal or just curiosity. It covers storing values in variables, using functions to manipulate those variables, and controlling the flow of those functions with repetition and conditionals.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Strategies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/classes/math-strategies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/classes/math-strategies/</guid>
      <description>Math Strategies&#xD;#&#xD;2023–2024&#xA;Course Description&#xD;#&#xD;Students who have been identified as needing additional support in mathematics will be recommended for and placed into the Mathematics Strategies course. This course is designed to prepare students to meet the current state graduation requirements established by the NJ Department of Education. Placement is determined by the administration. Students will be graded as Pass/Fail.&#xA;Graduation Assessment Requirements Explained&#xD;#&#xD;Aside from passing courses and earning credits, to graduate high school you must also demonstrate proficiency in both English and math on an approved assessment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summer Work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/classes/summer-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/classes/summer-work/</guid>
      <description>Summer Work 2023&#xD;#&#xD;All the work below is recommended, but not required.&#xA;Algebra I/Honors Calculus&#xD;#&#xD;Work through the appropriate Get Ready course on Khan Academy. I suggest starting with the quizzes to see where you need work.&#xA;Get ready for Algebra I Get ready for Calculus AP Computer Science A&#xD;#&#xD;Work through the first two units in Carnegie Mellon&amp;rsquo;s CS1: Intro to Programming. That link will take you to registration page with a code prefilled.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yearbook Club</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/clubs/yearbook-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/clubs/yearbook-club/</guid>
      <description>Yearbook Club&#xD;#&#xD;2021–2022&#xA;Yearbook Club is for students who wish to contribute to Valorem but are not enrolled in Yearbook Publishing. All are welcome and the only requirement for membership is to be a regular contributor. That means conducting interviews or submitting photos that document the who and what of the school year.&#xA;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested, you can visit me in room 47 or reach out through email. Meetings will happen based on individual availability.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
